<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Joshua Bautista</title>
    <link>https://EJoshuaB.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Joshua Bautista</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 22:37:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://EJoshuaB.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introductory Real Analysis and Topology Notes</title>
      <link>https://EJoshuaB.github.io/post/realanal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 22:37:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EJoshuaB.github.io/post/realanal/</guid>
      <description>Simply notes from an oly guy.&#xA;Metric Spaces A metric space is defined like groups are, over some set of points \(M\) and some distance function \(d\) called a metric. Formally \(d: M \times M \mapsto \mathbb{R}_{\geq 0}\) Any metric space has the following conditions for \(x,y,z\in M\):&#xA;\(d(x,y) \geq 0\) with equality at \(x=y\) \(d(x,y) = d(y,x)\) \(d(x,y) \leq d(x,z) + d(z,y)\), so the triangle inequality holds. Note that this is enough to imply that \(d\) is a continuous function in \(M\) by using the triangle inequality ‘on a line.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bijections Are Funny</title>
      <link>https://EJoshuaB.github.io/post/bijections-are-funny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EJoshuaB.github.io/post/bijections-are-funny/</guid>
      <description>A personal favorite style of problem of mine are problems that can seem very scary but admit pretty cute/short bijection solutions, so here&amp;rsquo;s a short collection of a couple of them I did recently, with a bit of motivation and a very handwavy explanation of them.&#xA;On the easier side we have a C1 from the 2014 IMO Shortlist. The statement is as follows:&#xA;IMO Shortlist 2014 C1 Let \(n\) points be given inside a rectangle \(R\) such that no two of them lie on a line parallel to one of the sides of \(R\).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Im glad I failed</title>
      <link>https://EJoshuaB.github.io/blog/2024/08/12/im-glad-i-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EJoshuaB.github.io/blog/2024/08/12/im-glad-i-failed/</guid>
      <description>Reflecting on my non-medal performance Last July I was able to compete at the 65th IMO held in the UK as PHI1, which was a lot of fun. Being at the lectures, hanging out with my team, thinking about the problems after the test, and being in the community that I had dreamed of being in since I was like 11 was surreal to me. That being said I get to the test with no sleep on the first day but prepared on the next and my score ended up being 5/0/0 7/0/0, a full solve meaning I guaranteed myself an HM but 4 points away from a total that would have garnered me a medal, and this was perhaps the best result I could have asked for.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo XMin</title>
      <link>https://EJoshuaB.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://EJoshuaB.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>XMin is the first Hugo theme I have designed. The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book. Basically I wanted a simple theme that supports a navigation menu, a home page, other single pages, lists of pages, blog posts, categories, tags, and RSS. That is all. Nothing fancy. In terms of CSS and JavaScript, I really want to keep them minimal.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
